<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ribosome | Sitio en español</title>
    <link>/es/tags/ribosome/</link>
      <atom:link href="/es/tags/ribosome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ribosome</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>es</language><copyright>© Maria Dermit, {2020}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu89765a528fbe3e89fbea23b995128687_292554_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Ribosome</title>
      <link>/es/tags/ribosome/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subcellular mRNA Localization Regulates Ribosome Biogenesis in Migrating Cells</title>
      <link>/es/publication/maddie-ehr-delivery-episode-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/es/publication/maddie-ehr-delivery-episode-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; Translation of ribosomal protein-coding mRNAs (RP-mRNAs) constitutes a key step in ribosome biogenesis, but the mechanisms that modulate RP-mRNA translation in coordination with other cellular processes are poorly defined. Here, we show that subcellular localization of RP-mRNAs acts as a key regulator of their translation during cell migration. As cells migrate into their surroundings, RP-mRNAs localize to the actin-rich cell protrusions. This localization is mediated by La-related protein 6 (LARP6), an RNA-binding protein that is enriched in protrusions. Protrusions act as hotspots of translation for RP-mRNAs, enhancing RP synthesis, ribosome biogenesis, and the overall protein synthesis in migratory cells. In human breast carcinomas, epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT) upregulates LARP6 expression to enhance protein synthesis and support invasive growth. Our findings reveal LARP6-mediated mRNA localization as a key regulator of ribosome biogenesis during cell migration and demonstrate a role for this process in cancer progression downstream of EMT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;RPmRNA_poster.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;RPmRNA_poster.pdf&#34;&gt;2020 RPmRNA Poster (letter)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
